Mothers. Daughters. Rebels.
Suffragette is a drama, history film directed by Sarah Gavron.
Based on true events about the foot soldiers of the early feminist movement, women who were forced
underground to pursue a dangerous game of cat and mouse with an increasingly brutal State.
Maud Watts, played by Carey Mulligan.
Edith Ellyn, played by Helena Bonham Carter.
Arthur Steed, played by Brendan Gleeson.
Violet Miller, played by Anne-Marie Duff.
Emmeline Pankhurst, played by Meryl Streep.
Sonny Watts, played by Ben Whishaw.
Suffragette is a 2015 historical drama film about women's suffrage in the
United Kingdom, directed by Sarah Gavron and written by Abi Morgan.
The film stars Carey Mulligan, Helena Bonham Carter, Brendan
Gleeson, Anne-Marie Duff, Ben Whishaw, and Meryl Streep.
Filming began on 24 February, 2014.
It is the first feature film to be shot in the Houses of Parliament.
The film was released in the United Kingdom on 12 October, 2015 by the French film
company Pathé through its British distributor 20th Century Fox.
Originally scheduled to be released by Relativity Media, the film was ultimately released in
a limited release in North America on 23 October, 2015 by Focus Features.
The film explores themes of london, england, biography,
feminist, period drama, woman director.
The tone is dark and emotional.